cemex.com 2016-12-04

# Privacy Policy | CEMEX

* * *

Online Privacy Statement (“Privacy Statement”)

## 1\. Scope

CEMEX is a global organization, with legal entities, business processes, management structures and technical systems that cross borders. This Privacy Statement applies to all CEMEX owned website domains, including social media sites and those of our wholly owned subsidiaries (“Website”), except that a privacy policy or statement specific to a particular CEMEX program, product, or service may supersede or supplement this Privacy Statement.

CEMEX is committed to protecting our customers’ right to privacy. For the purposes of this Privacy Statement a “customer” (or “you”) is anyone ordering, registering or making use of a Website. This Privacy Statement does not apply to any companies that CEMEX does not wholly own or to people that CEMEX does not employ or manage.

## 2\. Your Right to Privacy

Personal identifiable information is data that could identify a specific individual such as name, addresses, e-mail addresses, and telephone numbers (“PII”). Where a customer voluntarily chooses to supply CEMEX with its PII this data will be used exclusively for providing our customer with the information or service requested by him/her under the terms and conditions made available for him to consult prior to his/her disclosure of PII. Furthermore, CEMEX does not sell or otherwise release your PII to third parties for the purpose of allowing them to market their products and services to you.

## 3\. Your Privacy Preferences

Your browser may have cookies switched on. A “cookie” in this context, is a small file which is placed on your hard drive when you visit a website. This Website uses cookies and Google analytics to make your navigation of the Website easier and to gather statistical information. Google Analytics helps us to accurately estimate the number of visitors to the Website and volumes of usage. This ensures that the service is available when you want it and fast.

**By continuing to use this Website, you agree to CEMEX’s use of cookies for the limited purposes described above.**

At CEMEX we promote a culture of transparency around privacy and believe that the more information you have about your privacy settings the better you will be able to control the PII you disclose. For further information about how to switch off cookies, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). This link will take you to another website that is opened in a new window on your browser. CEMEX is not responsible for the content of the [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) website.

## 4\. Links to Non-CEMEX websites 

Our Websites may contain links to other sites which are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Statement. If you access other sites using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy statement, which may differ from ours. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit.

CEMEX may also provide social media features that enable you to share information with your social networks and to interact with CEMEX on social media sites (i.e. CEMEX’s Official Facebook Page). Your use of these features may result in collection or sharing of information about you, depending on the privacy preferences that you set up in your account and on the social media site you are using. We encourage you to review the privacy policy and settings on the social media sties with which you interact to makes sure you understand the information that may be collected, used and shared by those sites.

## 5\. Collection of PII

If during the customer’s visit to a Website, the customer orders products or services, enters a competition or submits other information to CEMEX, the customer may be providing CEMEX with PII.

CEMEX does not knowingly collect information from children. We encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online and mobile activities and interests.

## 6\. Sensitive Information

Sensitive Personal Data is information that reveals racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or health or sexual orientation of an individual. Please do not submit any sensitive personal data to CEMEX. We are not interested in collecting, using, storing or otherwise processing this type of information.

## 7\. Use of PII

CEMEX collects, exports, and uses PII to better serve its customers. Such collection is done with appropriate notice and consent along with required filing with data protection authorities, where required.

## 8\. The Purpose of CEMEX’s Data Retention

PII is held for the lifetime that your subscription is kept active through their use. Your subscription helps CEMEX contact you effectively. CEMEX does not collect any additional information about you other than outlined above.

## 9\. International Transfers

CEMEX may share its customer’s PII with other companies within the CEMEX Group, and/or third party suppliers that process data on our behalf.

Since CEMEX operates globally, this may mean that we could transfer our customer’s data to other countries, including countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). In all circumstances, CEMEX will take steps to ensure that the required filing with data protection authorities are made thereby ensuring that your PII receives the same level of protection as within the EEA and that this data is kept secure and used only in accordance with our instructions and for the purposes we have indicated to you at the time of collection of the PII, where required.

CEMEX reserves the right to disclose our customer’s PII as required by law or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our right and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request form a regulator or any other legal process served on us.

## 10\. Safeguarding Your PII

CEMEX values the trust you place in us. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, CEMEX uses reasonable and appropriate physical, technical, and administrative procedures to safeguard the information we collect and process.

## 11\. Changes to this Privacy Statement

We keep our Privacy Statement under regular review and reserve the right to modify this Privacy Statement from time to time. We will place any updates on this Website.

## 12\. Contact Information

Should you have any questions or comments about any of the above, please contact [ethos@cemex.com](mailto:ethos@cemex.com) for assistance.
